So here's back to the case of Romania.
We're trying to get from
Arad to Bucharest.
And we're going to think about what the
search tree looks like and what an
algorithm for on-the-fly discovery
of plans might look like.
And that's going to lead us to
the general search algorithm.
So here's a search tree.
When you start off, you've only
got the top of the tree.
You've got to start state.
Now in principle, there's all
this green stuff that's
mathematically defined.
There is a rest of the tree.
But unless you've done something wrong
you haven't constructed this dotted
green stuff in code yet.
So how's search going to work?
Well we're going to start at the very
top and we're going to build downward
in some way.
As we go, we're going to maintain a
collection of potential plans, which
are nodes in this tree, and
that collection is going
to be called a fringe.
This fringe is plans that we are
still considering that may
lead us to the goal.
And again we're going to try to expand
as few tree nodes as possible until we
find a goal.
So at this point, the only potential
plan we've got on our fringe is the
one that says, empty plan,
you're at Arad.
OK well that expands, so I might
take that off the fringe.
And it turns into three longer plans--
one that gets me to Sibiu,
you that gets me to
Timisoara, and one to Zerind.
Now on my fringe is these three plans.
I can't consider them all at once.
I can't extend them all
simultaneously.
So I'm going to have to pick one.
I'm going to take something off.
Maybe I'll take off the one to Sibiu.
And then I expand it.
And then it has longer plans.
And now my collection of plans under
consideration are these four-length
two plans and the two-length
one plans.
They're all sitting in my
fringe and I keep going.
And eventually I'm going to consider a
plan and discover it achieves my goal.
And I'll be happy and declare victory
and return that solution.
OK?
That's Tree Search.
So here's the algorithm
in pseudo code.
We're not going to process the pseudo
code in depth, but I want to show you
how it breaks down.
You'll have a chance to go through
this in much greater
detail in your projects.
So what does Tree Search do?
Well you pass in a problem.
We'll get to strategy in a bit.
You pass in a problem and you do
something over and over again.
What you do is you check.
And if there are no plans that you're
currently considering then you can't
achieve your goal and
you return failure.
You say, goal not achievable.
If there's still a set of plans
that might work, you pick one.
It's a leaf node on the tree, but it's
just a partial plan in your fringe.
So you pick something.
And then if that plan you just picked
happens to achieve your
goal, you're done.
You have a plan for achieving
your goal and you do your
goal-achieving dance.
If it doesn't, then you expand this
node and all of its children--
they're all longer plans--
they all go back into the fringe.
So that's the cycle.
The important ideas are, there's a
fringe which is all of the plans that
may yet work, there's expansion which
is picking something out of the
fringe, and if it's not a goal already,
putting in all of the
extensions of that plan,
the expansions.
And there's your exploration strategy,
which is all these things sitting on
the fringe.
Some of them are good ideas.
Some of them are bad ideas.
Which one should I do next?
So that's the main question.
And this is going to basically define
all of the search algorithms we're
going to study.
What fringe nodes do you explore next?
So let's do an example of Tree Search.
So let's say, what does it look like?
We start off with a fringe.
So we have our fringe here.
And then we actually have our
tree which we're going
to build as we process.
Really the key object in
the code is the fringe.
The tree's kind of there.
It exists in back pointers, so
from a node you can figure
out how you got there.
But really the fringe
is the key object.
The tree is object it makes sense
to think about on slides.
I'm going to draw them both
in some of these cases.
So let's think, what
are we going to do?
We start off with a tree which is just
S. And that means on our fringe is the
empty plan, congratulations you're
still at S. We have to pick one.
So there's no choice.
We pick S and we expand it.
And that means back on the fringe goes S
to D, S to E, and S to P. And that's
kind of equivalent to expanding out the
tree with D, E and P. And now the
fringe is these nodes.
What do I take off next?
E. All right.
So off comes E. And what
are its successors?
S to E to H. S to E to R. And this
is equivalent to E having
now H and R as children.
And now my fringe is this kind
of periphery of the tree.
I won't keep drawing the
fringe in both places.
What do I pop next?
S to E to R. There may be multiple ways
on my fringe of achieving R, at
least in the algorithms
as they are right now.
So S to E to R pops off.
And then on to my fringe goes S to E
to R to F. And that R right now has
this child F.
What should I pop off next?
S-E-R-F, serf.
We pop off the serf.
S-E-R-F--
and now this has two children.
One with C-R-F, and one
with G. Am I done?
Strictly speaking, you're not done.
And this will be more important for
some algorithms than others.
Strictly speaking, your successors go on
the fringe and only when they come
off the fringe could you possibly
declare victory.
But what shall I pop off?
Next maybe we'll pop this off.
It passes the goal test.
And now we have a solution
and we return it.
So without expanding the whole
tree, we found a goal.
We did it relatively efficiently.
I would say this is a successful use of
Tree Search to find a goal without
having to expand something
large and exponential.
This algorithm is called CS188 Guided
Search and is not, in general,
available to you.